Hello everyone and welcome to English Pot.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and if you've been
following along with us recently you'll
know that we have a series about
interviewing in English and so today we have
the very last episode of that series.
That's right today is the last part of our
interview series and we're basically
just saying goodbye and we're doing
some other things when you're leaving
an interview. It's very important the
things that you say. That's right
because this is the last thing that you're
going to do in the interview so it's
what your interviewer will remember.
So let's take a listen to today's
dialogue and we'll be back in a moment.
Well Rebecca, is there anything
else you need to know for now?
I don't think so Mr. Parsons. I think you
have covered all the main points for me.
Okay well listen here's my business
card with my mobile number.
If any other questions spring to
mind don't hesitate to contact me.
Of course you can
also call Miss Childs too.
Great. When can I expect to hear from you?
Well we are finishing the short list
interviews tomorrow so we will certainly
have a decision made by early next week.
Miss Childs will call you to
discuss more on Monday or Tuesday.
How does that sound?
That sounds perfect. Thank you very
much for taking the time to speak to me Mr.
Parsons. The pleasure
is all mine Rebecca.
I hope to hear from you
very soon. Absolutely.
Thanks for coming
Rebecca. Goodbye.
All right great. So really good things
from Rebecca. She sets some very
interesting things, key things there.
So why don't we take a look at those on
language takeaway. Language takeaway.
At the beginning of the
end of the interview, Rebecca says,
"Listen, I think you have covered all the
main points for me." So this is
after Mr. Parsons asks her if she has
questions and this word
covered is very important.
That's right. So if we talk about cover
to cover the main points or to cover a
topic, it needs to discuss it
thoroughly or to have it finished.
Right. So if I still have questions,
we have not covered everything.
But if I did ask all the questions that I
have, then we've covered everything.
So the verb here is to cover.
That's right. Okay. And Mr.
Parsons says, "Well, you know what? Here's
my business card with my mobile number.
" So this word business
card, key elements of any
interview or any business situation.
As you say, a key part of any business
interaction. So a business card
is a very small card, usually sick.
And it has a person's name, job, phone
number, and sometimes email address now
on the card. So the information can change.
But it's a contact
card basically for one person. That's
right. So this is very important to have
around, especially in situations like this.
Okay. And moving on,
he also told her that
if she has any other
questions to not hesitate
and to contact him.
This is a very common phrase.
Don't hesitate to contact me or
don't hesitate to ask. That's right.
So to hesitate means
to be nervous about something or to maybe
not do it because you're uncomfortable.
So, you know, Marco, I want to ask you
something, but I'm not sure if I want to
ask you, maybe you'll be
angry or so I'm hesitating.
Right. Okay. So we're here to hesitate.
You have doubts.
I have doubts. And so he says,
"Don't hesitate to contact me.
" That means any questions, any
issues, please call me. Okay. Very good.
And Mr. Parsons said that
they are finishing the short list of
interviews tomorrow.
So what does it mean a short list?
Well, a short list is something we
talk about during the interview process
because the interviewer, so in this
case, Mr. Parsons will have a long list of
people who want the job.
And maybe after the first interview,
he will cut the list down to very
small number of people, it's 10 or 15.
And that is called
the short list.
So those are the people who did
well on the first interview, but who
maybe should come back
for a second or third interview.
That's right. Okay. Very good.
So a lot of great things there.
Why don't we take a break. Let's
go back and listen to the dialogue.
Let's see what Mr. Parsons and
Rebecca said. And we'll be back with some
really good phrases that you
can close off an interview with.
Well, Rebecca, is there anything
else you need to know for now?
I don't think so, Mr. Parsons. I think you
have covered all the main points for me.
Okay. Well, listen, here's my
business card with my mobile number.
If any other questions spring to
mind, don't hesitate to contact me.
Of course, you can also call Ms.
Childs too.
Great. When can I expect to hear from you?
Well, we are finishing the
short list interviews tomorrow,
so we will certainly have a
decision made by early next week.
Ms. Childs will call you to discuss
more on Monday or Tuesday.
How does that sound? That sounds perfect.
Thank you very much for taking the time
to speak to me, Mr. Parsons.
The pleasure is all mine, Rebecca.
I hope to hear from you
very soon. Absolutely.
Thanks for coming,
Rebecca. Goodbye.
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a
look at those phrases we
mentioned on fluency builder.
Fluency builder. So let's go back to the
beginning where Mr. Parsons is talking
about questions that Rebecca might have.
And so Mr. Parsons says, "If any other
questions spring to mind,
don't hesitate to contact me.
" So this phrase, spring
to mind is very interesting.
What does this mean? Well, basically, if
something springs to your mind or springs
to mind, it means that it
comes very suddenly and
quickly into your mind. It
just pops into your head.
Wow. So to spring
or springs in this case
is like jumping. So something
hits your mind very quickly.
It comes into your
mind very quickly.
So, oh, I don't really
have any ideas, Marko,
for that party next
week. But, you know, if
anything springs to mind,
you should let me know.
Okay. So if you have any
sudden ideas or anything
you suddenly remember, that's
what it means to spring to mind.
Okay. So taking a look at these expressions
that Rebecca used when she's leaving.
For example, you know
that you finished the interview
and a typical question
that you want to make
is, "When can I expect
to hear from you?
" This is a great question
at the end of an interview,
because it's basically
a way of saying, "Listen,
I'm interested in this
job. When will you
call me about it?" And
so the phrase, "When can I
expect to hear from you
means, when will you tell
me your decision?"
That's right. But it's a lot
more polite and formal
and better than saying,
"When are you going to
call me?" Yeah, you would
never say that in an,
well, you just, you wouldn't
want to say that in an
interview, because it makes
you sound desperate like
you really need the job.
In this case, you know, "When
can I expect to hear from you?
" It's like, "Oh, well, you know, I
hope that you'll get in touch with me.
" That's right. Okay. And
well, he explained that they're
short-listing everything
and that they will be
in touch with her very
soon. And she said, "Wow,
that sounds perfect. Thank
you very much for taking
the time to speak to
me." Okay. So this phrase,
"Thank you very much for
taking the time to speak to me.
" It's very long. But you know it, thank
you very much. The key here is for taking
the time to do something.
Now, what does this mean?
What's another
way we can use this?
It's basically saying, "Thank
you so much for giving me
an opportunity to talk
to you. I know you're very
busy and I know you
don't have a lot of time,
so thank you very much for
taking the time to speak to me.
" All right. So you
could even use
this with a teacher at school. You know,
you have a question, your teacher is busy,
but your teacher makes
some time to meet with you.
Say, "Hey, listen,
professor or listen, teacher.
Thank you so much for
taking the time to speak to me.
" Mm-hmm. You're just demonstrating that
you appreciate the effort and the time.
And you're being very
polite. That's right. Okay.
And now the last phrase
when Rebecca is leaving
the room, that you're
shaking hands maybe,
and Rebecca says, "I hope
to hear from you very soon.
" You can say, "I hope
to hear from you soon.
" But in this case,
she's saying, "Listen,
I really want this job."
She doesn't want to say,
"Call me, you know,
call me tomorrow.
" She says, "I hope
to hear from you soon.
I hope that this works out
that I get the job." Right.
So she's basically demonstrating
a lot of interest saying,
"Well, I really like the
job and I really would
like for you to call me
and give me good news,
so I hope to hear
from you soon." Exactly.
So let's listen to today's
dialogue. One more time,
and we'll be back
in a moment to talk a
little bit more about
how to end an interview.
Well, Rebecca, is there anything
else you need to know for now?
I don't think so, Mr. Parsons. I think you
have covered all the main points for me.
Okay. Well, listen.
Here's my business card
with my mobile number.
If any other questions
spring to mind don't
hesitate to contact me.
Of course, you can also
call me as a child, too.
Great. When can I expect to hear from you?
Well, we are finishing
the short list interviews
tomorrow, so we will
certainly have a decision
made by early next
week. Miss Childs will
call you to discuss more
on Monday or Tuesday.
How does that sound?
That sounds perfect.
Thank you very much for
taking the time to speak to me,
Mr. Parsons. The pleasure is all mine,
Rebecca. I hope to hear from you very soon.
Absolutely.
Thanks for coming, Rebecca. Goodbye.
So this is a great way of ending an
interview. Rebecca did a really good job.
And I think there are a
couple of suggestions
or tips that you would
like to give our users.
Yeah. Well, one of them
is don't, at the end of
the interview, ask the
person if you have the job.
They'll say we will be in touch or
thank you so much for coming in.
But if they don't say
we would really like to
have you join this company,
then you probably shouldn't ask.
You should say, you know, I, when can I
expect to hear from you? That's more polite.
Because I think a lot
of times if you didn't
get the job, it makes the
interviewer feel very uncomfortable.
But also it's just a
polite thing to do.
So be careful with
that. And I've also been
told from people in
business that if you do
receive a job offer,
don't accept right away,
say I will think about it and
I'll get back in touch with you.
Okay. Kind of like a strategy maybe to
better negotiate the terms and conditions.
Exactly. So you want
to, you want to take
those, that information,
you want to go home,
you want to think about it, talk about it
with your wife or your husband and decide,
is this something I want?
And then you can contact the employer.
Right. Yeah. I think
that's a very good idea.
And also, I think
it's not a wise thing
to call or contact the
employer asking if you've
got the job or asking if
they have any news yet,
because I think that can
be a little bit annoying.
But if they say we will
be in touch on Tuesday
and it's a week later and they never got
back to you, send a follow-up. Of course.
A follow-up is an
email or a letter or we've
been a phone call where you say, "Listen,
I'm really glad I got to meet you today.
I hope that we have the opportunity
to work together in the future.
Please be in touch, sincerely, and
then your name." Kind of like a reminder.
Is a reminder. Like I want the job,
here's my information. Let's do this.
Or at least if I didn't get the job, let me
know that I didn't get it. Yeah, exactly.
All right. So a lot
of great advice here.
Great things coming.
And we'll be back again
with another series. We're going
to have a presentation series.
So be sure to keep
an eye out for that.
And if you have any other
questions or comments,
we're always at EnglishPods.com
where you can find us.
We'll see you there. Bye, guys. Bye.